# SFAN PARDO

236 Livingston St., Apt 22E | Brooklyn NY, 11201 | 631-335-6519 | seanpardo@gmail.com

### **PRODUCT MANAGER**

Product | Design | Analytics

Senior Product Manager focused on developing best in class digital experiences that are driven by data and design principles resulting in an improvement in user experiences and key business metrics.

#### **QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY**

Business	Product Management, SaaS/Enterprise Software, Customer Development, Business Intelligence
Software	Jira, InVision, Sketch, Github
Design	Design Sprint, UX Research, Usability Testing, Mobile First Design, Responsive, Web Form Design
Technology	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJs, MySQL, MongoDB, JSON, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes
Analytics	AB Testing, Tableau, HEAP Analytics, Google Analytics, Periscope, Power Bi,

#### **EDUCATION**

## **CORNELL UNIVERSITY, ITHACA NY**

May 2007

Bachelor of Arts, College of Arts and Science – Government

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **LEARNVEST,** New York, NY

10/2016-Present

#### PRODUCT MANAGER

- Improved Node.js/Backbone Planning tool experience to further enhance the workflow and organization of data points to empower Planners delivering advice to clients
- Implemented API integration of Zendesk that provides ticket creation capability within the Planning experience
- Redesigned Asset Allocation feature to improve flexibility of choices, leveraging GraphQL to surface data
- Created Keystone CMS to surface instructional content via a ReactJS app to support Planners
- Worked with Data team to implement front-end HEAP analytics tool to analyze performance of each Planning feature

## **OVATIONTIX.COM, New York, NY**

04/2015-10/2016

## PRODUCT MANAGER

- Enhanced customer facing experience of SaaS platform by implementing a Responsive Checkout platform to allow B2C users to personalize their businesses checkout experience
- Conducted 50+ hours of client interviews and customer research to assess and prioritize feature needs across several client segments and initiate 5 -day Design Sprint
- Increased overall checkout volume and conversion to lift total client revenue by 11%
- Collaborated with outbound Sales team to prioritize roadmap and understand new prospects in the pipeline and their needs

## MINDSPARK INTERACTIVE (IAC, INC.), New York, NY

01/2014-08/2014

#### PRODUCT MANAGER

- Lead all product initiatives on Chrome Extension Ecommerce product in concert with development, design, marketing, and legal teams through agile development cycle
- Supported increase in LTV of 37%

 Conducted AB Testing (double control) to test new feature performance and run holdback tests to assure consistent performance from past implementations

## **AMERICAN EXPRESS**, New York, NY

11/2012-12/2013

# NEW PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT, MANAGER

- American Express Prepaid Card: Redesigned registration form and onboarding- leveraging web form design principles, leading to an increase in conversion of registration by %22
- Best Buy Cobranded Prepaid Card: Collaborated with client, internal web/mobile, and marketing teams to develop core BRDs, FRDs, wireframes, and working prototypes
- Disney Prepaid Responsive Site: Worked with partner, design agency, and development teams to develop
  core requirements and design new Prepaid product that included physical armband and respective
  responsive site

## **INFOSYS TECHNOLOGIES**, New York, NY

09/2010-08/2012

# E-COMMERCE, CONSULTANT

- Cisco Systems World Wide: Managed implementation of a global CRM and loyalty program across 4
  geographic regions from business requirements, use cases, design, build and test. Supported SIT/QA/UAT
  testing under agile methodology
- Victoria's Secret: Developed a user experience strategy for Victoria Secrets Omni-channel retailing initiative using omni-channel research. Product Owner through sprint planning and daily scrums that were driven by user stories
- Pfizer: Defined capabilities and requirements for a Pfizer digital marketing platform, designed value diagram to report ROI for stakeholder evaluation and validation.

## **ALTON LANE**, New York, NY

12/2009-08/2010

### F-COMMERCE OPERATIONS

- Focused on enhancing customer experience across multiple channels and optimized marketing metrics, order processing, logistics, and product development in a global company
- Developed initial customer database to analyze using demographic analytics, for eventual Salesforce.com migration, resulting in 20% quarterly revenue growth
- Defined scope of point-of-sale system, using e-commerce analytics and customer feedback

## ORRICK HERRINGTON AND SUTCLIFFE, New York, NY

08/2007-11/2008

# STRUCTURED FINANCE - PARALEGAL

- Drafted, edited and distributed opinions, memorandums and offering circulars for multiple CDO and CDS transactions, simultaneously accumulating to over 3 billion in collateralized debt obligations.
- Oversaw corporate compliance and conducted due diligence (good standing, lien searches etc...)

**LEADERSHIP** 

**STREETWISE PARTNERS** 

2016-Ongoing

Career Mentor